<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<uml:Model name="Bian" xmi:id="BianID" xmi:version="2.1" xmlns:uml="http://www.eclipse.org/uml2/3.0.0/UML" xmlns:xmi="http://schema.omg.org/spec/XMI/2.1">
 <eAnnotations source="Objing" xmi:id="AnnotationID">
  <contents name="exporterVersion" xmi:id="contentID" xmi:type="uml:Property">
   <defaultValue value="3.0.0" xmi:id="stringID" xmi:type="uml:LiteralString"/>
  </contents>
 </eAnnotations>
 <packagedElement name="Product Feature Type Helper SD" visibility="public" xmi:id="29d2802e-1394-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c" xmi:type="uml:Package">
  <packagedElement name="ProductFeatureTypeValues" xmi:id="9e924c3c-0d94-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c" xmi:type="uml:Enumeration">
   <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
    <body/>
   </ownedComment>
   <ownedAttribute name="BankingService" xmi:id="9f924c3c-0d94-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c">
    <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
     <body>
      A classification that distinguishes between instances of product features according to the core banking services, functionality and/or objectives of banking.

e.g. deposit services, exchange services, etc.

The primary reason for the contract with the client are the banking services. These services can be classified as follows:
1. Selling services
2. Financial Instruments Exchange
3. Financial Stock Management
4. Financial Transfers
5. Financial Risk Transfer
6. Business Operating
7. Advisory
8. Reporting
     </body>
    </ownedComment>
    <type href="pathmap://UML_LIBRARIES/UMLPrimitiveTypes.library.uml#String" xmi:type="uml:PrimitiveType"/>
   </ownedAttribute>
   <ownedAttribute name="AdministrationService" xmi:id="1dab3b67-0d94-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c">
    <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
     <body>
      A classification that distinguishes between instances of product features according to administrative tasks related to the Banking Product or Service.
     </body>
    </ownedComment>
    <type href="pathmap://UML_LIBRARIES/UMLPrimitiveTypes.library.uml#String" xmi:type="uml:PrimitiveType"/>
   </ownedAttribute>
   <ownedAttribute name="AccessService" xmi:id="d81a637a-0d94-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c">
    <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
     <body>
      A classification that distinguishes between product features according to way of the banking services can be accessed.

The access to services becomes more and more important in the evolving markets. 
We need to separate different parts:
1. The physical access to the infrastructure that allows access to the bank (where)
2. The authorization of different parties to use the services of the bank (who)
3. The agreed procedure to have access to different services (how)
4. The services that are available for the different parties (what)
     </body>
    </ownedComment>
    <type href="pathmap://UML_LIBRARIES/UMLPrimitiveTypes.library.uml#String" xmi:type="uml:PrimitiveType"/>
   </ownedAttribute>
   <ownedAttribute name="PriceFeature" xmi:id="bde6c68f-0d94-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c">
    <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
     <body>
      A classification that distinguishes between instances of product features according to the cost/profit that is related to Banking Products or Services.

In all commercial offerings, there is an agreed cost for both parties (e.g. the interest arrangements are in both directions). The pricing structure of products or packages is a service that gives the possibility to the client to adapt his costs to his individual situation.
We see different generic categories in the pricing structure of the different products.
1. Compensations
2. Prices
3. Fees
4. Discounts
     </body>
    </ownedComment>
    <type href="pathmap://UML_LIBRARIES/UMLPrimitiveTypes.library.uml#String" xmi:type="uml:PrimitiveType"/>
   </ownedAttribute>
  </packagedElement>
  <packagedElement name="BankingServiceTypeValues" xmi:id="343a4e99-0e94-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c" xmi:type="uml:Enumeration">
   <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
    <body/>
   </ownedComment>
   <ownedAttribute name="SellingService" xmi:id="da8b93eb-0f94-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c">
    <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
     <body>
      A classification that distinguishes between instances of Banking Services according to delivering services without the need for a formal (written) agreement.

Selling services are services that are delivered at clients and prospects without a written contract. These services are used as a means to build-up or broaden the relationship with clients and prospects. Some of these services are advisory services as described separately.

Includes following services (e.g.)
1. Information Services
2. E-purse and PaySec
3. Mortgage Advice
4. Calculators

Generic Services are:
1. Elementary Services
The elementary services are easily accessible and make it possible to start already a relationship with prospects without directly starting the extensive procedure of client identification. These services are flexible and should therefore not be integrated in the expensive, complex and robust processes of the other products. E.g. the data quality will be different.
Elementary services can be made available for real clients. In this case the elementary services can be extended to the normal services.
2. Help-me-buy services
These are services to help the client to match his needs to the product&amp;services offering in the brand. 
3. Offering Services
These are services in the context of a concrete product to decide if the offering is adequate to the concrete situation of the client. A concrete example is a simulation of a loan.
     </body>
    </ownedComment>
    <type href="pathmap://UML_LIBRARIES/UMLPrimitiveTypes.library.uml#String" xmi:type="uml:PrimitiveType"/>
   </ownedAttribute>
   <ownedAttribute name="FinancialInstrumentExchangeService" xmi:id="a8f6af12-1094-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c">
    <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
     <body>
      A classification that distinguishes between instances of Banking Services according to the sale or trade of financial instruments.

Financial Instruments Exchange are the services where the bank is a point of sale for the exchange/trade of financial instruments. Essentially, these are services that are not directly related with an account, although they can be integrated with products that are linked to accounts. The essential elements are the management of the rates that are used, the commissioning for the trade transaction and the valuation of (more complex) financial instruments 

Includes following services (e.g.)
1. Foreign Exchange
2. Buy/Sell funds
3. Buy/Sell shares

Generic Services are:
1. Buy/Sell
The trade of financial instruments against another financial instrument. This can be in the same class, such as foreign exchange, but can also be in different classes, such as shares for cash. 
The process behind the trade can be different.
2. Broker Services
These services are comparable with Buy/Sell. The difference is that the bank is only the broker and doesnt have the risk of intake
3. Valuation
Linked to a portfolio of Financial Instruments the valuation for clients of the owned values is an essential service (not for cash)
     </body>
    </ownedComment>
    <type href="pathmap://UML_LIBRARIES/UMLPrimitiveTypes.library.uml#String" xmi:type="uml:PrimitiveType"/>
   </ownedAttribute>
   <ownedAttribute name="FinancialStockManagementService" xmi:id="2e9c3a2f-1094-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c">
    <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
     <body>
      A classification that distinguishes between instances of Banking Services according to depositing of financial instruments.

Financial Stock Management is the offer to clients of an account to keep their cash or other financial instruments. As stock management offers the availability of the infrastructure to keep instruments, this includes also all services to manage the instruments.  Although the word stock refers to a physical preservation, also negative preservation, as in credits can be included.

Includes following services (e.g.)
1. Cash Handling
2. Custody

Generic Services are
1. Deposit/Withdraw
Deposit or withdraw the instruments on or from an account. 
2. Define/Change limits
As accounts are a sort of financial stock, limits of minima and maxima can be defined to facilitate the financial stock management. There are limits that can be defined for deposit and withdrawal (e.g. debit card limit). The limit for deposit means that every surplus above the limit will lead to a transfer to a given account or another action. These limits should be at least dependent on the (type of) channel and on the account itself (multiple limits are needed).
If limits are reached an action should be taken. Feedback to the order responsible and the client should be made. E.g. credits limits should be variable in time.
3. Accrual interest (for lending and saving)
For each account arrangements can be made on the compensation of interest (in two directions: surplus and shortages). Penalty interest for late repayments is a specific example
4. Financial Instruments Maintenance
The maintenance of financial instruments (mainly coupon of bonds)..
     </body>
    </ownedComment>
    <type href="pathmap://UML_LIBRARIES/UMLPrimitiveTypes.library.uml#String" xmi:type="uml:PrimitiveType"/>
   </ownedAttribute>
   <ownedAttribute name="FinancialTransferService" xmi:id="6cefb763-1094-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c">
    <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
     <body>
      A classification that distinguishes between instances of Banking Services according to transfer of financial instruments between accounts.

Financial transfer is the transfer between two accounts of instruments (cash or other values)
Includes following services (e.g.)
1. Payment
2. Direct Debit
3. Standing Order

Generic Services are:
1. Outgoing transfers
The possibility to do transfers from one account to another account. In case of cash accounts, these are payments. But other transfers can be foreseen (e.g. at asset accounts). The range of accounts where transfers can go will change this service and the process behind it. (Domestic payments, international payments, etc.)
2. Incoming transfers
The possibility to accept transfers from other accounts. The availability of the account for other accounts (and also different payment systems) to do payments is the determining factor of this service
3. Multiple Transfer Set-up
The possibility to set-up future transfers following different criteria. A difference should be made in the invoke procedure. Is the future payment invoked by an agreed event (direct debit) or is it invoked automatically at a specific time (standing order)
     </body>
    </ownedComment>
    <type href="pathmap://UML_LIBRARIES/UMLPrimitiveTypes.library.uml#String" xmi:type="uml:PrimitiveType"/>
   </ownedAttribute>
   <ownedAttribute name="FinancialRiskTransferService" xmi:id="7f10bf8c-1094-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c">
    <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
     <body>
      A classification that distinguishes between instances of Banking Services according to transfer of financial risks between parties.

This service gives the possibility to transfer the financial consequences of a risk to the financial services provider. In the banking environment this is limited to transfer of financial risks. But examples of more extended services can be found in the insurance industry.

Includes following services (e.g.)
1. No recourse factoring
2. Guaranteed Funds
3. Life Insurances
4. Non-life Insurances

Generic Services
1. Customer Risk Valuation
This is the service to evaluate the risk of the event covered. This should help the client to know exactly the remaining risk for him and have no hassle when an event occurs.
The evaluation of collateral is also included here.
2. Claims Handling
Is the treatment of the intake of a claim, the evaluation of the causing claim event and the financial loss. For most services in the banking environment this should be standardized.
3. Risk Changing Adaptations
The change of the factors that determine the risk should lead to a adaptation of the coverage (e.g. depreciation of an insured asset). If the client is responsible to report these changes, a service should be available to alert him and facilitate this reporting. He can also voluntary change his cover.
     </body>
    </ownedComment>
    <type href="pathmap://UML_LIBRARIES/UMLPrimitiveTypes.library.uml#String" xmi:type="uml:PrimitiveType"/>
   </ownedAttribute>
   <ownedAttribute name="BusinessOperatingService" xmi:id="9127a4bd-1094-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c">
    <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
     <body>
      A classification that distinguishes between instances of Banking Services according to taking over business operations from client.

Business operating is the service to take over some activities of the client linked to the management of a risk where the client transferred the financial risk.  Business operating is present in the leasing and factoring.

Includes following services (e.g.)
1. Maintenance of an asset (Leasing)
2. Collection of receivables
3. (Early) buy-in of an asset.

Generic Services are:
1. Asset Rental
The service to rent the asset from the financial institution and therefore avoid the formal buy transaction. 
2. Asset Maintenance Activities
The outsourcing of the activities with the goal to maintain the value of the asset. In leasing this is the physical maintenance of the asset. In factoring, it is the activity to maintain the value of the account receivables for the client.
3. Deferred Asset Acquisition
This is the possibility to acquire the asset at the end of the rental contract at agreed conditions or at market value.
     </body>
    </ownedComment>
    <type href="pathmap://UML_LIBRARIES/UMLPrimitiveTypes.library.uml#String" xmi:type="uml:PrimitiveType"/>
   </ownedAttribute>
   <ownedAttribute name="InformationService" xmi:id="48c54afd-1094-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c">
    <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
     <body>
      A classification that distinguishes between instances of Banking Services according to providing information as a service.

This service gives the possibility to offer information as a service. In the banking environment this is known in the form of advisory services and reporting services. More and more offering data and insight information is offered as a service.

Includes following services (e.g.)
1. Reporting Services
2. Advisory Services
3. Financial Information Services
     </body>
    </ownedComment>
    <type href="pathmap://UML_LIBRARIES/UMLPrimitiveTypes.library.uml#String" xmi:type="uml:PrimitiveType"/>
   </ownedAttribute>
  </packagedElement>
  <packagedElement name="InformationServiceTypeValues" xmi:id="4a23455a-1194-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c" xmi:type="uml:Enumeration">
   <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
    <body/>
   </ownedComment>
   <ownedAttribute name="AdvisoryService" xmi:id="5db38469-1194-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c">
    <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
     <body>
      A classification that distinguishes between instances of Information Services according to purpose of advising the destinee of the information.

Advisory is the contracted service to deliver customized advice (once or regularly) in a specific way and for a specific purpose. This service is explicitly negotiated and agreed upon and therefore essentially different from a selling service. This does not mean that it should be priced separately as it can be integrated in a total offer towards clients. Advisory are all products that can be classified as decision support for the clients. In this sense there is an overlap with selling services as some selling services are also advisory although not (always) negotiated.

Includes following services (e.g.)
1. Key Plan/Vario Plan
2. Financial Advisory
3. SME Advisory 
4. Portfolio Management
5. Client Care 
6. Subsidies Advisory

Generic Services are:
1. Information Build
This is the service where for the specific purpose of decision support, data is transformed to information that is structured in a way that the client can easily understand and overview his situation. E.g. a consolidated portfolio overview or a risk profile of the client
2. Knowledge Build
The service where information is built into knowledge. Included are all analysis methods that give a client an in-depth knowledge of his (benchmarked) position. E.g. All different tools for risk analysis and portfolio ratios.
3. Personalized Advice
Build on information about the clients situation and an analysis, a personalized advice can be delivered. An advice is the description of the actions that the client can take to optimize his position. E.g. advice to align portfolio on risk profile.
     </body>
    </ownedComment>
    <type href="pathmap://UML_LIBRARIES/UMLPrimitiveTypes.library.uml#String" xmi:type="uml:PrimitiveType"/>
   </ownedAttribute>
   <ownedAttribute name="ReportingService" xmi:id="5652112a-1294-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c">
    <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
     <body>
      A classification that distinguishes between instances of Information Services according to purpose of reporting with regard to operational and managerial aspects of banking product or service agreements, relations, portfolio's, etc.

Reporting are all the services, linked to a specific product or to the whole of the product portfolio that clients have bought. 

Includes following services (e.g.)
1. Statement (Transactional Overview)
2. Balance Inquiry
3. Portfolio (Position Overview)
4. GSM alerts

Generic Services are:
1. Transactions Reporting
The reporting of all transactions that are done on the level of a client or a product (account). Distinction should be made for all channels that are used for the transactions.
2. Position Reporting
The reporting of the (balance) position of an account or a set of accounts.
3. Event Reporting
This service is linked to both services above. If a transaction cannot be executed because insufficient balance on the account is one example of an event.  This event reporting can be configured by the client.
     </body>
    </ownedComment>
    <type href="pathmap://UML_LIBRARIES/UMLPrimitiveTypes.library.uml#String" xmi:type="uml:PrimitiveType"/>
   </ownedAttribute>
   <ownedAttribute name="FinancialInformationService" xmi:id="4918d343-1294-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c">
    <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
     <body/>
    </ownedComment>
    <type href="pathmap://UML_LIBRARIES/UMLPrimitiveTypes.library.uml#String" xmi:type="uml:PrimitiveType"/>
   </ownedAttribute>
  </packagedElement>
  <packagedElement name="PriceFeatureTypeValues" xmi:id="5056028a-1294-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c" xmi:type="uml:Enumeration">
   <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
    <body/>
   </ownedComment>
   <ownedAttribute name="CompensationTimingsFeature" xmi:id="f2d9e49d-1294-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c">
    <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
     <body>
      A classification that distinguishes between instances of Banking Services according to when costs/revenues will be applied.

The timing of the compensation (when clients really pay for the service) is one of the essential elements of the pricing structure.
For each of the other components the Compensation Timings will be defined. 

Generic Components are:
1. Periodicity
The period wherein the price is calculated. Annual, monthly, daily. 
2. Payment Timing
The concrete timing of the payment for the client. This can be independent of the periodicity and the variability of the cost drivers
3. Variability
The variability of the cost driver reflects in fact the used cost drivers of the cost that are made visible towards clients. This can be event driven, based on time passed, time spent, etc.
     </body>
    </ownedComment>
    <type href="pathmap://UML_LIBRARIES/UMLPrimitiveTypes.library.uml#String" xmi:type="uml:PrimitiveType"/>
   </ownedAttribute>
   <ownedAttribute name="PricingFeature" xmi:id="253d94b5-1294-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c">
    <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
     <body>
      A classification that distinguishes between instances of Price Features according to the type of price.

Pricing Arrangements are the intrinsic prices for financial instruments or financial services. They reflect the value of the instrument or service that is bought.

Generic Components are
1. Buying Prices
These are prices for financial instruments or currency exchanges. The principle of price lists is used.
2. Interest
Interest rates have a particular treatment for different products. From client point of view the interest calculation is important for its costs. The technical establishment of the interest rate is of lesser importance 
3. Renting Fees
Renting fees are for example used for leasing and safe boxes.
4. Risk Pricing
The pricing of financial risk transfer towards the bank. Used in insurances in all forms, but also in credits.
     </body>
    </ownedComment>
    <type href="pathmap://UML_LIBRARIES/UMLPrimitiveTypes.library.uml#String" xmi:type="uml:PrimitiveType"/>
   </ownedAttribute>
   <ownedAttribute name="FeeFeature" xmi:id="d903bdcb-1294-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c">
    <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
     <body>
      A classification that distinguishes between instances of Price Features according to the type of fee.

Fees are costs that are paid by clients to use the infrastructure of the bank to organize and structure their financial management and to do their financial transactions. They are different from the intrinsic costs of financial activities. We describe here the different fees we recognized. These are all costs as clients experience them, and they do not have to reflect the real costs for the bank.
A lot of the components will follow the structure of the underlying pricing Arrangements (e.g. the costs for a credit can be expressed as an increase of the interest rate or commissions are expressed as a percentage of the insurance premium)

Generic Components are:
1. Set-up fee Inc. fee for changes
The fee that is paid by the client to set-up a service. (e.g. Contract Costs for a mortgage)
2. Management Fee
The fee that is paid by the client to maintain the infrastructure so that this is available for clients (e.g. price for a bundle)
3. Transactions Fee
The fee that is paid for the execution of a transaction by clients (e.g. withdrawal)
4. Communication Fee
The fee that is paid for the communication towards clients. This fee is mostly for reporting and information (e.g. sms-alerts)
5. Taxes
The tax that is immediately paid by clients on the price of interest and fees (e.g. tax deducted directly by the bank on interest).
6. Commissions
The fee that is paid to the bank as an intermediary for financial instruments or other (financial) services (e.g. commissions for funds or insurances.
     </body>
    </ownedComment>
    <type href="pathmap://UML_LIBRARIES/UMLPrimitiveTypes.library.uml#String" xmi:type="uml:PrimitiveType"/>
   </ownedAttribute>
   <ownedAttribute name="DiscountFeature" xmi:id="239f16f3-1294-e911-823e-069871e4ec9c">
    <ownedComment xmi:id="commentid">
     <body>
      A classification that distinguishes between instances of Price Features according to type of discounts.

In the one hand, discount Arrangements are the commercial instruments to adapt the cost of the client to his personal situation. On the other hand, discount arrangement is used in marketing campaigns. Especially these arrangements can be over different products and it should be possible to link them to different parameters.  

Generic Components:
1.    Package Discount
The discount of buying different services in one package.
2.    Subscription
The discount when the use of a service is guaranteed over an agreed time period (safe box over 3 years)
3.    Maximum /Fixed Cost
The discount expressed as a maximum/fixed cost if the cost driver crosses a fixed limit, mostly related to transactions 
4.    Absolute/Relative Discount
The discount at the level of a product or collection of products expressed in percentage or absolute amount.
5.    Loyalty Schemes
The accumulation of units that can be exchanged for benefits of other discounts.
     </body>
    </ownedComment>
    <type href="pathmap://UML_LIBRARIES/UMLPrimitiveTypes.library.uml#String" xmi:type="uml:PrimitiveType"/>
   </ownedAttribute>
  </packagedElement>
 </packagedElement>
</uml:Model>